[
  {
    "id": "804",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "2. A Machine Learning Specialist is designing a system for improving sales for a company. The objective is to use the large amount of information the company has on users behavior and product preferences to predict which products users would like based on the users similarity to other users. What should the Specialist do to meet this objective?",
      "answers": [
        "Build a content-based filtering recommendation engine with Apache Spark ML on Amazon EMR",
        "Build a collaborative filtering recommendation engine with Apache Spark ML on Amazon EMR",
        "Build a model-based filtering recommendation engine with Apache Spark ML on Amazon EMR",
        "Build a combinative filtering recommendation engine with Apache Spark ML on Amazon EMR"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Build a collaborative filtering recommendation engine with Apache Spark ML on Amazon EMR"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "805",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "3. A Mobile Network Operator is building an analytics platform to analyze and optimize a companys operations using Amazon Athena and Amazon S3.\nThe source systems send data in .CSV format in real time. The Data Engineering team wants to transform the data to the Apache Parquet format before storing it on Amazon S3. Which solution takes the LEAST effort to implement?",
      "answers": [
        "Ingest .CSV data using Apache Kafka Streams on Amazon EC2 instances and use Kafka Connect S3 to serialize data as Parquet",
        "Ingest .CSV data from Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and use Amazon Glue to convert data into Parquet.",
        "Ingest .CSV data using Apache Spark Structured Streaming in an Amazon EMR cluster and use Apache Spark to convert data into Parquet.",
        "Ingest .CSV data from Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and use Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose to convert data into Parquet."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Ingest .CSV data from Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and use Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose to convert data into Parquet."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "806",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "4. A city wants to monitor its air quality to address the consequences of air pollution. A Machine Learning Specialist needs to forecast the air quality in parts per million of contaminates for the next 2 days in the city. As this is a prototype, only daily data from the last year is available. Which model is MOST likely to provide the best results in Amazon SageMaker?",
      "answers": [
        "Use the Amazon SageMaker k-Nearest-Neighbors (kNN) algorithm on the single time series consisting of the full year of data with a predictor_type of . regressor",
        "Use Amazon SageMaker Random Cut Forest (RCF) on the single time series consisting of the full year of data.",
        "Use the Amazon SageMaker Linear Learner algorithm on the single time series consisting of the full year of data with a predictor_type of regressor.",
        "Use the Amazon SageMaker Linear Learner algorithm on the single time series consisting of the full year of data with a predictor_type of classifier."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Use the Amazon SageMaker Linear Learner algorithm on the single time series consisting of the full year of data with a predictor_type of regressor."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "807",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "5. A Data Engineer needs to build a model using a dataset containing customer credit card information. How can the Data Engineer ensure the data remains encrypted and the credit card information is secure?",
      "answers": [
        "Use a custom encryption algorithm to encrypt the data and store the data on an Amazon SageMaker instance in a VPC. Use the SageMaker DeepAR algorithm to randomize the credit card numbers.",
        "Use an IAM policy to encrypt the data on the Amazon S3 bucket and Amazon Kinesis to automatically discard credit card numbers and insert fake credit card numbers.",
        "Use an Amazon SageMaker launch configuration to encrypt the data once it is copied to the SageMaker instance in a VPC. Use the SageMaker principal component analysis (PCA) algorithm to reduce the length of the credit card numbers.",
        "Use AWS KMS to encrypt the data on Amazon S3 and Amazon SageMaker, and redact the credit card numbers from the customer data with AWS Glue."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Use AWS KMS to encrypt the data on Amazon S3 and Amazon SageMaker, and redact the credit card numbers from the customer data with AWS Glue."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "808",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "6. A Machine Learning Specialist is using an Amazon SageMaker notebook instance in a private subnet of a corporate VPC. The ML Specialist has important data stored on the Amazon SageMaker notebook instances Amazon EBS volume, and needs to take a snapshot of that EBS volume. However, the ML Specialist cannot find the Amazon SageMaker notebook instances EBS volume or Amazon EC2 instance within the VPC. Why is the ML Specialist not seeing the instance visible in the VPC?",
      "answers": [
        "Amazon SageMaker notebook instances are based on the EC2 instances within the customer account, but they run outside of VPCs.",
        "Amazon SageMaker notebook instances are based on the Amazon ECS service within customer accounts.",
        "Amazon SageMaker notebook instances are based on EC2 instances running within AWS service accounts.",
        "Amazon SageMaker notebook instances are based on AWS ECS instances running within AWS service accounts."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Amazon SageMaker notebook instances are based on the EC2 instances within the customer account, but they run outside of VPCs."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "809",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "7. A Machine Learning Specialist is building a model that will perform time series forecasting using Amazon SageMaker. The Specialist has finished training the model and is now planning to perform load testing on the endpoint so they can configure Auto Scaling for the model variant. Which approach will allow the Specialist to review the latency, memory utilization, and CPU utilization during the load test?",
      "answers": [
        "Review SageMaker logs that have been written to Amazon S3 by leveraging Amazon Athena and Amazon QuickSight to visualize logs as they are being produced.",
        "Generate an Amazon CloudWatch dashboard to create a single view for the latency, memory utilization, and CPU utilization metrics that are outputted by Amazon SageMaker.",
        "Build custom Amazon CloudWatch Logs and then leverage Amazon ES and Kibana to query and visualize the log data as it is generated by Amazon SageMaker.",
        "Send Amazon CloudWatch Logs that were generated by Amazon SageMaker to Amazon ES and use Kibana to query and visualize the log data"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Generate an Amazon CloudWatch dashboard to create a single view for the latency, memory utilization, and CPU utilization metrics that are outputted by Amazon SageMaker."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "810",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "8. A manufacturing company has structured and unstructured data stored in an Amazon S3 bucket. A Machine Learning Specialist wants to use SQL to run queries on this data. Which solution requires the LEAST effort to be able to query this data?",
      "answers": [
        "Use AWS Data Pipeline to transform the data and Amazon RDS to run queries.",
        "Use AWS Glue to catalogue the data and Amazon Athena to run queries.",
        "Use AWS Batch to run ETL on the data and Amazon Aurora to run the queries.",
        "Use AWS Lambda to transform the data and Amazon Kinesis Data Analytics to run queries."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Use AWS Glue to catalogue the data and Amazon Athena to run queries."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "811",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "9. A Machine Learning Specialist is developing a custom video recommendation model for an application. The dataset used to train this model is very large with millions of data points and is hosted in an Amazon S3 bucket. The Specialist wants to avoid loading all of this data onto an Amazon SageMaker notebook instance because it would take hours to move and will exceed the attached 5 GB Amazon EBS volume on the notebook instance. Which approach allows the Specialist to use all the data to train the model?",
      "answers": [
        "Load a smaller subset of the data into the SageMaker notebook and train locally. Confirm that the training code is executing and the model parameters seem reasonable. Initiate a SageMaker training job using the full dataset from the S3 bucket using Pipe input mode.",
        "Launch an Amazon EC2 instance with an AWS Deep Learning AMI and attach the S3 bucket to the instance. Train on a small amount of the data to verify the training code and hyperparameters. Go back to Amazon SageMaker and train using the full dataset",
        "Use AWS Glue to train a model using a small subset of the data to confirm that the data will be compatible with Amazon SageMaker. Initiate a SageMaker training job using the full dataset from the S3 bucket using Pipe input mode.",
        "Load a smaller subset of the data into the SageMaker notebook and train locally. Confirm that the training code is executing and the model parameters seem reasonable. Launch an Amazon EC2 instance with an AWS Deep Learning AMI and attach the S3 bucket to train the full dataset."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Load a smaller subset of the data into the SageMaker notebook and train locally. Confirm that the training code is executing and the model parameters seem reasonable. Initiate a SageMaker training job using the full dataset from the S3 bucket using Pipe input mode."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "812",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "10. A Machine Learning Specialist has completed a proof of concept for a company using a small data sample, and now the Specialist is ready to implement an end- to-end solution in AWS using Amazon SageMaker. The historical training data is stored in Amazon RDS.\nWhich approach should the Specialist use for training a model using that data?",
      "answers": [
        "Write a direct connection to the SQL database within the notebook and pull data in",
        "Push the data from Microsoft SQL Server to Amazon S3 using an AWS Data Pipeline and provide the S3 location within the notebook.",
        "Move the data to Amazon DynamoDB and set up a connection to DynamoDB within the notebook to pull data in.",
        "Move the data to Amazon ElastiCache using AWS DMS and set up a connection within the notebook to pull data in for fast access."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Push the data from Microsoft SQL Server to Amazon S3 using an AWS Data Pipeline and provide the S3 location within the notebook."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "813",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "11. A Machine Learning Specialist receives customer data for an online shopping website. The data includes demographics, past visits, and locality information. The\nSpecialist must develop a machine learning approach to identify the customer shopping patterns, preferences, and trends to enhance the website-for better service and smart recommendations. Which solution should the Specialist recommend?",
      "answers": [
        "Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA) for the given collection of discrete data to identify patterns in the customer database.",
        "A neural network with a minimum of three layers and random initial weights to identify patterns in the customer database.",
        "Collaborative filtering based on user interactions and correlations to identify patterns in the customer database.",
        "Random Cut Forest (RCF) over random subsamples to identify patterns in the customer database."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Collaborative filtering based on user interactions and correlations to identify patterns in the customer database."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "814",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "12. A Machine Learning Specialist is working with a large company to leverage machine learning within its products. The company wants to group its customers into categories based on which customers will and will not churn within the next 6 months. The company has labeled the data available to the Specialist. Which machine learning model type should the Specialist use to accomplish this task?",
      "answers": [
        "Linear regression",
        "Classification",
        "Clustering",
        "Reinforcement learning"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Classification"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "815",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "13. The displayed graph is from a forecasting model for testing a time series. One upwar trending line above another with separation. Considering the graph only, which conclusion should a Machine Learning Specialist make about the behavior of the model?",
      "answers": [
        "The model predicts both the trend and the seasonality well",
        "The model predicts the trend well, but not the seasonality.",
        "The model predicts the seasonality well, but not the trend.",
        "The model does not predict the trend or the seasonality well."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The model predicts both the trend and the seasonality well"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "816",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "14. A company wants to classify user behavior as either fraudulent or normal. Based on internal research, a Machine Learning Specialist would like to build a binary classifier based on two features: age of account and transaction month. The class distribution for these features is illustrated in the figure provided. Fraudulent in the middle surrounded by normal. Based on this information, which model would have the HIGHEST accuracy?",
      "answers": [
        "Long short-term memory (LSTM) model with scaled exponential linear unit (SELU)",
        "Logistic regression",
        "Support vector machine (SVM) with non-linear kernel",
        "Single perceptron with tanh activation function"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Support vector machine (SVM) with non-linear kernel"]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "817",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "15. A Machine Learning Specialist at a company sensitive to security is preparing a dataset for model training. The dataset is stored in Amazon S3 and contains\nPersonally Identifiable Information (PII). The dataset: Must be accessible from a VPC only. Must not traverse the public internet. How can these requirements be satisfied?",
      "answers": [
        "Create a VPC endpoint and apply a bucket access policy that restricts access to the given VPC endpoint and the VPC.",
        "Create a VPC endpoint and apply a bucket access policy that allows access from the given VPC endpoint and an Amazon EC2 instance.",
        "Create a VPC endpoint and use Network Access Control Lists (NACLs) to allow traffic between only the given VPC endpoint and an Amazon EC2 instance.",
        "Create a VPC endpoint and use security groups to restrict access to the given VPC endpoint and an Amazon EC2 instance"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["Create a VPC endpoint and apply a bucket access policy that restricts access to the given VPC endpoint and the VPC."]
    }
  },
  {
    "id": "818",
    "category": "Cloud Concepts",
    "info": {
      "subcategory": "ML Simulated Exam Questions",
      "questionType": "multiple choice 1",
      "question": "16. During mini-batch training of a neural network for a classification problem, a Data Scientist notices that training accuracy oscillates. What is the MOST likely cause of this issue?",
      "answers": [
        "The class distribution in the dataset is imbalanced.",
        "Dataset shuffling is disabled.",
        "The batch size is too big.",
        "The learning rate is very high."
      ],
      "correctAnswer": ["The learning rate is very high."]
    }
  }
]